何て優しいんだ！ あえて教えてくれてる そして導いてくれてる
While Killua returned to the Zoldyck
compound for a reunion with Alluka, who was locked up deep underground...
どうすれば より強くなれるか あんたは　自分より 強いと思った敵と対した時
I'd say there were six other cases
in which two people died...
逃げ切ることを前提に戦っている。
Our mother didn't believe Killua,
so that was another pair.
あんたは　いつか ゴンを見殺しにする。
Another pair died to satisfy her curiosity.
もしも　明日 シュートを倒せなければ
Even after she was convinced, she sacrificed two more pairs to verify
how the other victims were chosen. Then Milluki
ゴンの元から消えなさい。
exchanged the lives of two pairs
of tourists for some cheap toys.
ナックル　シュートとの対決に 臨む
Alluka x And x Something
負けたほうが…
Sure, a few pictures are no problem, Muna-san.
相手に割り符を渡す！
I'm just taking Alluka and Kalluto for a walk.
はなから
Incredible!
全力で行くぜ！
Hey, Muna...
スピードで競えば翻弄される
Eat this. Hmm?
ダメージ覚悟で 迎え撃つ！
Huh? Oh, sorry... He likes to make requests.
目で追うな　感じるんだ！
Kill him for me.
オーラで！
Figuring out the tourist incident wasn't easy...
くっ…。
But since another butler paid the
price for the butler's incident, it was easy to track down the victims.
遅かったけど…　感じ取れた
The criteria that determines who dies is different for more than two people.
それにしても…　何だ？
Perhaps there are different
rules for when a pair dies, and when many people die.
力が…　溢れて来る！ あっ…。 時間です。
Zoldyck butlers are trained in
a facility on our property. At the exact moment Kasuga died, every butler in her class at that
facility was wrung to death.
利息がつきます。
Her head teacher and specialized teachers also died.
あっ…。
Butlers from other classes...
な…　何なんだ　こいつは…
Friends from her orphanage...
貸したんだよ　お前に 俺のオーラをな。
All people she was close to.
オーラを…　貸した？
Still, that she liked all of her
classmates was impossible, right?
ちなみに利息はトイチ １０秒で１割！
It becomes clear when you look at her
hospitalized biological mother.
早く返さねえと　とぶぜ！ 時間です。
Every month, she could only meet
her mother for half an hour.
利息がつきます。
Records from Kasuga's student days say she
loved her mother most in the world.
能力名は「ハコワレ」。
But her mother, in the hospital, survived.
そいつはマスコットの ポットクリンだ。
Well, people change...
ポットクリンへの攻撃は 時間の無駄だぜ。
Love and hate are two sides of the same coin. I agree, but that wasn't the case here.
おめぇの周りで利息の増加を 告げるだけ。
It wasn't that she began to hate her mother.
無害ゆえに無敵。
Rather, she found someone she loved more.
フッ　ちょっと目障りだがな。 時間です　利息がつきます。
Kasuga had just begun a relationship.
あっ…。
She'd spent even less time with her lover
than she had with her mother.
くっ！
But wait...
まただ　全然　痛くないし
You didn't investigate her past after the fact.
逆に力が…　みなぎる！
You chose her to test after learning her past. Oh, you could tell?
時間です　利息がつきます。
Yeah, that's right.
一気に倍近く!?
We used her to confirm our suspicions.
今　さらに貸したからな！
Since our butlers aren't allowed to
have relationships, or they're killed.
１８０オーラほどよ。 １８０オーラ？
The first incident made it clear
that this power was dangerous.
何なんだ その数字は　さっきから… 知らなさそうだな その面はよ　こら。
Capable of destroying the Zoldyck
family, if we didn't understand it.
１８０オーラってのは 精神エネルギーを数値化したもんだ。 オーラってのは 体内に蓄積されていて
After investigating the first incident
and reaching a conclusion, the second incident confirmed it.
そのＭＯＰは 訓練で増やせるため個人差がある。
If you fail to grant four of Alluka's requests, you must pay with your life.
さらに　そのオーラを一度 外へ放出する量も　しかり。 訓練による増加が可能なわけだ。
When the price is two lives, you and the person you love most will die.
つまり　いくら体内のＰＯＰが 多くても 実際に体外に出せるＡＯＰが 修行不足などにより少なければ 戦闘じゃ絶対的に不利なわけだ。 分かるな？　こら。
When more than two must be sacrificed, you and the person you love most will die, along with, in order, those you've
spent the most time with.
おめぇが「堅」によって 体外に　とどめておける
So Kasuga's mother didn't die because she
hadn't spent enough time with her.
オーラのマックスは 目算で約１８００オーラ。 臨戦態勢時　精神エネルギーは
And Kasuga's lover died,
despite his short time with her.
基本　１秒に１オーラ 消費されて行く。
This is a problem.
しかし　いざ戦闘に入れば
Isn't it?
「凝」　「流」　「堅」など 応用技を使うため
Killua will make a wish to Alluka, to restore Gon.
消費量は増大し　基本の約６倍から １０倍のスピードで減って行く。
If Killua makes the wish
技のレベルが高いほど オーラの消費量は 増えるってわけだ。
and lets someone else fulfill the requests, there shouldn't be any problem.
いいか？　こら。 オーラの操縦が下手な　おめぇは 単純計算で１秒１０オーラ。
But I'm sure Killua will do things
the other way around.
てめぇは　昨日の戦いで ２０分ほどでパンク。
Brother! Alluka...
つまり　通常戦闘で 約１万２０００オーラを 使い果たした。 うぅ…。
Killua will have someone else make the wish, and will then attempt to fulfill the
consequent requests himself.
おめぇのＡＯＰは 約１８００オーラ。
Sorry about leaving you down
here for so long, Alluka.
しかし　「ジャジャン拳」が発動し 「ジャン！」と発した瞬間
I'm sorry. It's okay! I'm really happy!
拳に集中するオーラは ２０００を超えていた。
I've missed your scent...
それは　タメの長さや防御力を 犠牲にして 拳にオーラを集めるなど
The leader of the monsters was strong enough
to force Netero to resort to the Rose.
必殺技固有のリスクを負った 状態のみの特殊効果。 最初の３回で　およそ５５００ おめぇは　「ジャジャン拳」によって オーラを消費した。
To defeat one of its subordinates, Gon's restriction and covenant must
have been harder on him than death.
ここまでの合計は １万７５００オーラ！ うぅ…。
A wish to reverse that would far exceed
the power of money and medical science.
そして　４発目 「あいこ」を撃つ直前　力尽きた。
The wish will likely be granted. And then, Killua will do whatever
he can to fulfill Alluka's requests.
技を出し切るのに必要な消費量を 途中の倍と考えると
Killua will receive requests he cannot fulfill.
４０００ものオーラが 使われた計算。
Still, Killua will try his best, and fail halfway.
この消費量は 「グー」でも「パー」でも変わらねえ。
Mission failed.
ただし　属性が違う上に 修行不足の「パー」は ４０００ものオーラを消費しても あの程度。
The one he loves most, or the
one he's spent most time with...
恐らく　５００オーラくらいの威力しか 保てなかったってわけだな。
Either way, the restored Gon will still die.
つまり　おめぇの潜在オーラの マックスは
Huh? Huh? Oh.
およそ２万１５００オーラ！
Am I wrong?
ぐっ…　予想外の攻撃。 ギャハハハハ！ 計算は苦手みてぇだな。
When you mentioned that "both" would die, were you referring not to Killua and Gon, but to Killua and yourself?
だが　ここからが本番だ よく聞け　こら　ボケ！ あぁ…。
Yes, that's right. I have issues, but you are just as bad.
おめぇが借り入れたオーラが 利息込みで 現在残っている潜在総オーラ量を 超えた時
And if things go wrong, it won't only be Killua, Gon, and me.
おめぇは　とぶ！
Every Zoldyck will die.
オーラは 通帳残高みたいなもの
I'm thinking that this wish will cost
tens of thousands of lives.
使えば　どんどん減るし 利息は　逆にかさんで行く！
So you'll probably die, too. That's why your comment surprised me.
２０００くらいは　もう消費済み。 見ろよ。
Oh, this is a problem...
さっきの　さ…　３倍!? 絶対　間違ってるよ！
Brother, die.
さっきから２３分しか 経ってないのに！ 正確には１２０秒。
Okay, sure.
これが「雪だるま式に 借金が増える」ってやつだ。
Bang! I'll ask Killua to follow proper procedure
when he makes his wish.
くっ…。 おめぇのオーラは 俺が貸した分 ３９０を足しても２万切った。
If Killua either refuses,
or agrees, but you feel he's lying, I want you to dispose of Alluka.
借金は着々と増えて行く。
He has no combat abilities.
仮に　おめぇが黙って 立ってるだけでも２６０秒後
You can consider him an ordinary child.
つまり４分２０秒後には… とぶ！
We just don't know where he came from.
とんだら　どうなるの？
Third Election for the 13th Chairman
1) Pariston — 258 (39%)
2) Cheadle — 49
3) Botobai — 31
4) Ickshonpe — 28
5) Mizaistom — 27
ポットクリンが トリタテンに変身。
6) Morel — 18
7) Teradein — 17
8) Saccho — 15
9) Sanbica, Bushidora — 14
11) Loupe — 11
12) Cutie, Biscuit, Linne — 10
15) Tsezguerra — 9
16) Knov, Kanzai — 6
18) Kite, Satotz — 4
20) Menchi, 6 others — 3
27) Saiyu, 3 others — 2
31) Gon, Hanzo, 21 others — 1 There were 68 absentees.
３０日間　破産者につきまとう。
Absentees — 68              Turnout — 89.7% The turnout was 89.7%.
その間は完全に「絶」状態。
Oh, dear... Oh, dear... Oh, dear.
つまり念能力は全く使えない。
This is strange. In the second vote, there were
thirty-three absentees.
後悔しても遅ぇぞ　こら！
This time, we have sixty-eight absentees. More Hunters were absent.
だから 今まで使わなかったのか
So they chose to put their licenses
on the line by not voting at all? What's going on?
俺のために…
Why would they go that far?!
ナックル！
from anyone who's committed both offenses?
ありがとう 行くぞ！
Yes, I suppose we have no choice.
１５０ってとこだな 今のパンチ。
Please send them a letter
that says these two things: They must bring their licenses to headquarters.
くっ…。
And that we expect them to explain their absences.
差し引きで３０増えたぜ？ どうするよ　おい。
I don't know... Will that really be enough?
おめぇが借金を 完全に返し終わるまで
Once they lose their licenses,
violators gain exemption from the rules.
俺は　お前の攻撃で ダメージは受けねえ。
They no longer need to fear
the penalty for not voting.
そうだ　来い　こら！
Huh? But we put the proposal to a vote.
黙ってても４分しねえで とぶんだからな！
Besides, everyone was against the idea
手数は　おめぇの勝ち！
Yes, he's hard to deal with
だが　差し引きで言やぁ １００くらいしか返済してねえぞ。
because he readily accepts
suggestions that hurt him. And he'll even propose ideas
disadvantageous to him.
「焼け石に水」だな　おい。 利息の半分も返せてねえぞ　こら！
That's the one aspect that's
similar to Chairman Netero. And I don't like it!
絶対に「ジャジャン拳」は 食わねえぞ
So I have a proposal.
借金が１万を超えれば 俺の勝ちは確実
I think the twelve Zodiacs should give a speech before all of the Hunters.
時間です　利息がつきます。
We must express this election's importance!
こ…　これは…
Alluka's power has rules the rest of
the family doesn't know about. Brother, let's play shiritori.
気おされちゃダメだ
Okay, sure.
能力が未知なのは あっちも同じ…
Then...
俺は　人を傷つけるのは嫌いだ。
I'll start with the ending "A" in "Alluka"! The one that calls me "Brother" is the real Alluka.
だから逆に 傷つけなきゃ発動しない
The one that calls me "Killua"
そんな能力にした
is something else.
そんな奴だけを 相手にできるように だが…。
Brother, pat my head.
あっ…。
Sure.
認めるからこそ死力で 戦わねばならぬ時があること。 手が３個？
Killua's being a model big brother.
何で？　浮いてる
That's three requests down.
どんな能力だ？ こっちから仕掛けるか？
So a computer was no big deal...
落ち着け　「凝」で様子を見る！
S-S-Sorry, Papa...
「隠」は　使っていない
That means Alluka is ready.
実際に ３個の手は浮いている！ つまり　恐らく
Yep, Killua just has to make his wish.
操作系の能力者
Milluki, I want you to go over the rules again.
あの籠も謎
Ah, sure.
手を飛ばして 攻撃するだけなら
I'm aware of five rules.
必要のないもの 要は…
One. When someone fails to fulfill one of
Alluka's requests, causing them to reset, the request difficulty returns to level 1.
あの手に触れるのは危険！
That's the best time to make a wish to Alluka.
ヨーヨーか まずは　お手並み拝見
Two. Once Alluka starts making requests to someone, he will not switch his requests
to someone different.
素晴らしい手さばきだ あっ！
Three. If the person receiving Alluka's requests
dies before clearing them all, it's considered a failure, and at least one more will die.
速い！　手は…　おとり？
This was confirmed by experiment. Four.
) はっ！
If he doesn't know someone's name,
Alluka can't make requests of them.
((あんたは　自分より 強いと思った敵と対した時
The same person can't make two wishes in a row. That's all I know.
逃げ切ることを前提に 戦っている))
I'm not hiding anything from you! I swear on the deal we made.
ぐっ！
Why isn't Killua making a wish?
撃てなかった！ 体が意思の通りに動かない
He probably has some foolish idea...
これが…　呪縛！
If Killua makes a wish now, someone else will have to clean up the mess.
奴の反応が明らかに鈍った
That makes no sense.
何か　あったか？
Can he not save his friend first, and worry about the consequences later?
よせ！　考えるな
Papa...
悪い癖だ！　どんな事情であれ 全力で倒す！
Would his friend be happy to know
でなければ　彼に失礼だ！
that many lives were sacrificed to save him? No! That's what's going through his head.
強いし　速い！
His mind doesn't work the way ours do.
恐らく全てが　俺より上！
That's why you had Illu-nii use
his needles on him, right?
((あんたの弱点 それは　見切りの早さ))
Father, open the door.
「敵に　こうされたらヤバい」 とか考えちゃってる))
No. Make the wish in that room.
((相手が少しでも格上ならば もうＮＧ))
We cannot let you go outside.
((「何とか　勝とう」って気持は びた一文なくなる))
As I thought.
((選択は逃げの一手 負け犬の思考)) ((それは あんたのせいじゃ　ない))
They don't know about any of these rules.
((あんたに戦闘を教え込んだ 人物の責任))
Father, I am definitely your son.
((あんたは　いつか ゴンを見殺しにする)) くっ…。
You called Alluka "something that
came from somewhere else."
左目？
We're leaving.
左顔面が…　ない 今のは　素晴らしい反応
Something, if we haven't left the mountain in half an hour, kill my mother!
できるだけ　敵から離れろ))
Huh? Hey, Killua!
助けられたな　呪縛に でも　それじゃダメなんだ
If we've left the mountain in half an hour, I want you to kiss me on the cheek.
くっ…。
Got it?
自分より強い敵に 真っ向勝負を挑む
'Kay.
勝つために！
Mama!
チッ！　左が死角に！ あっ。
How... How can you issue such cruel commands?
ぐっ　まだだ
It's magnificent! You've grown up!
いい動きだ。
Damn! You're allowed to do that?
違う！　逃げてるだけだ！ 俺は 一度も戦っていなかった！
As long as only one wish is granted, you can give yourself options!
((もしも　明日 シュートを倒せなければ
Father, open the door.
電撃か。
Something is skilled at destroying,
but fixing isn't her forte.
怖いな。 構うか！　追え！
When she's fixing, she must touch the target,
or her power won't work.
ゴンとキルアが 割り符を懸けた戦いをしている ちょうど　その頃
If we've left the mountain in half an hour, I want you to kiss me on the cheek.